Guide to the Women's Fund for Health Education and Resiliency (HER) Records 2000-002
University of Houston Libraries Special Collections
- Publications, 1979-2011
  - Primer on Women's Health, 1984-1994
    - Fundraising (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - "B" Misc. (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Captain's B.H. Inc. (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Cytel Telecom (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Forms W3-W2, 1099-1096 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Northern Trust Signature Documents (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - "C" Misc. (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Briggs and Veselka (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Payroll (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Northern Trust Bank: Bank Reconciliations (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Advanta Business Cards (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - A Proposed Merger Agreement (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Northern Trust Inc., Misc. (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - Voided Checks (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Audit (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - Texas Employment Commission (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Primer Update/Brown Foundation (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - Update - Medical, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Update - Women's Health, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - What About Me? A Girl's Guide to Health - Master File, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - HN/WAM Placement Reports, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Evaluations, 2000-2002 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - English - Rewrite, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Women's Health Organization - Original Copy, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Update - Master, undated (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Update - A Woman's Health (Spanish), 2005 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - The Women's Fund Report, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Women's Health Matrix Awards Competition (1st Place), 1987 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Women's Health - Marketing, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Women's Health - Distribution, 1994-1997 (Box 24, Folder 31-32)
    - Women's Fund/United Way - Shaping Up Your Schedule, 2008 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Women's Health Symposium, 2010 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Primer- Spanish Translation, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Primer/Health Notes Request Form, 1995-2002 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Spanish/English Primer, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Primer, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Primer on Women's Health, 1984-1985 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Primer on Women's Health - Public Relations, 1989; 1991 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Health Notes, 1995-1999
    In 1995 the Women's Fund recognized that changes in the insurance industry meant that many women might change health care providers repeatedly over a lifetime. To help both patient and physician with this dilemma, Health Notes grew into a simple, practical strategy for a woman to collect and maintain a personal record of her medical history.
    - Correspondence and Examples, 1995-1999 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Publications Report, 2003; 2007; 2009 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Body Works Toolkit, 1994-2012
    - Cuestionario de Entrada del Padre o Persona al cuidad del Nino o Adolescente (Spanish) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Session 2 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Session 1 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Cuestionario de Entrada del Padre o Persona al cuidad del Nino o Adolescente – TX2 (Spanish) (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Health Fair Photos (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Long Range Planning (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Annual Plan (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Misc. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Staff Meeting (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - "What about me?" Questionnaire (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Long Range Planning Discussion (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Public Relations Committee (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - 4th-8th Annual Women and Girls Good Health Day Reports (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Financial Philosophy (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Long Range Planning Discussion (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Texas Southern University: Social Work Field Instructor (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Essay Contest/Scholarship Winners (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - United Way Grant Application (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Women and Girls' Good Health Day (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Sessions 1-8: Encuesta del Participante Sobre las Sesiones de BodyWorks (Spanish) TX 2 (Box 25, Folder 20-27)
    - The Women's Fund and Image University Volunteer Program (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - "What about Me?" Curriculum Guide (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Women and Girls' Good Health Day – Essay Contest Winners with news clippings (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - "Impressions" publications (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Cedarbrook Elementary Evaluations (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - What About Me? - A Girl's Guide to Health, 1996-2009
    - What About Me? A Girl's Guide to Health, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - What About Me? A Girl's Guide to Health, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - What About Me? (Curriculum), 2008 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - What About Me Author Bids: Frances Neighbors; Special Projects Coordinator, 1996-1999 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - What about Me? A Girls' Guide to Health- First Draft Curriculum Guide, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - What about me? – Planning, undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - What about me? – Curriculum Guide, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - What about me? – Curriculum Training, undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - What about me? – Curriculum Guide Materials, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - "What About Me?" Draft, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - "What about Me?" – Publication Shipping Request, 2009 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Harris County Juvenile Probation Department – Book Distribution: "What About Me?", 2002 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - "Which Weigh?" Publication, 2007-2008
    - Publication Draft, Spanish/English, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Budget, Publication Outline, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Review Meeting Agenda, 2007-2008 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Agenda for Production, undated (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Draft, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Historical Events and Newsletters, 1979-2006
    - Historical Events and Newsletters, 1979-2005 (Box 31, Folder 1-24)
    - Impressions Newsletter, 1997-2005 (Box 31, Folder 25-34)
  - Federally Qualified Clinics, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Leads and Special Events, 2002-2006 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Distribution Policy, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Health Notes, Design, and Printing, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Health Notes Cover Prototypes, undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Distribution Policies, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - University of Houston Evaluation Project, undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Medical Writers - Inactive Publications, 1994-1998 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Infertility Pamphlet and Questions to Ask Gynecologist, undated (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Diagnosis of Alcoholism: Dr. Lawrence, undated (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - What Every Woman Should Know about Breast Cancer, undated (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Publicity Binders, 1995-2005 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
  - Women and Health Draft Sent to Casey Neighbors from Moore Creative, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Women and Health: Draft Sent to Susan Moore, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Publications Committee, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - English – Woman and Health – Draft, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Health Equity Project, 2011 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Museum of Health and Medical Science, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Planners/Calendars, undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Campaign – "This is Deceptive Tactic", undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Mother/Daughter Sample, undated (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - HPV & U Brochures, 2010 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Bodywork Handouts, undated (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Resources- Just Think, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Eating Together, undated (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Just the Facts, undated (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Healthful Cooking, undated (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Say "Yes" to Family Meals, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Women and Girls' Good Health Day Information Sheet, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Translating- Houston Chronicle Article, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Graphic Designers/Illustrators, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Houston Business Journal – ADDY Awards, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Publication Committee, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Media Release Form, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Office Logistics, 2007-2008 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Distribution Policy, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - UH Research Project- Surveys, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Health Brochures- Other Sources, 1997-1999 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Women and Health: Revision, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - Curriculum, 2004 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Body Works – Boys – Sample, undated (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - Biennial Report - Eliminating Health Disparities in Texas, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "Y Yo Que?" (Spanish) Girls' Guide to Health folder, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Center for Research on Women with Disabilities. Removing Disability Disparities in Women's Health, 2011 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - The Women's Fund for Health Education and Research, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - The Women's Fund – Publication Content Graphics/Charts/Form, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Certificate of Registration – Publication Copyright, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Research: Capacity Enhancement Indicators (Yemile Mizrahi), undated (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Texas Children's Hospital Research Publication Draft, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Obesity Publication Outline, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Heart Attack Symptoms and Calling 9-1-1 - Campaign for Women, 2011 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Cite, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - Asian-American, Mother/Daughter events flyers, 2004-2008 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - A New Priority for Women's Health, undated (Box 26, Folder 50)
  - National Women's Health Week, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 51)
- Photographs, 1983-2000
  The Photographs series is comprised of photographs of Women's Fund fundraisers, seminars, members, luncheons, programs, and more.
  - Fundraisers Photos, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Saint Luke's Photos, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - W.H Meyer Seminar Photos, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Member Photos, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Photos – Depression, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Benefit Luncheon Photos, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Christmas Photos, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - What About Me? Photos, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - McGovern Seminar Photos, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Fundraiser Photos, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Fundraiser Photos, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Membership Coffee Photos, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Volunteer Recognition Program Photos, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - WHM Seminar Photos, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Lifetime Member Photos, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Membership/Memorial Photos, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - WHM Photos, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Benefit Lunches Photos, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - W&G GH Day, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Spring Seminar Photos, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Spring Seminar Photos, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Benefit Luncheon Photos, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Benefit Luncheon Photos, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - WHR Seminar Photos, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Benefits Luncheon Photos, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Annual Membership CO/EE Photos, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Presentations of Grants Photos, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Dr. Stehlum Photos, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - WHM Photos, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - Membership Lecture Photos, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - Spring Seminar Photos, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - W.R. Bishop Photos, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - Membership Programs Photos, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - McGovern Seminar Photos, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - Hadassah Photos, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - Membership Coffee Photos, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 36)
  - Benefits Luncheon Photos, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 37)
  - Members Coffee Photos, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - Volunteer Recognition Luncheon Photos, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - Fundraiser Photos, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - Member Lecture at Hermann Hospital Photos, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - Fundraiser Photos, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - New Board Members Photos, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - Herman Hospital Lecture Photos, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 44)
  - Member Coffee Photos, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 45)
  - Benefits Luncheon Photos, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 46)
  - Benefits Luncheon Photos, 2008 (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - Annual Membership Coffee Photos, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 48)
  - Membership Photos, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 49)
  - VOL. Lunch Photos, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 50)
  - Lifetime Membership Program Photos, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 51)
  - Membership Coffee Photos, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 52)
  - McGovern Seminar Photos, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 53)
  - Seminar Photos, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 54)
  - Membership Coffee Photos, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 55)
  - Spring Seminar Photos, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 56)
  - W.H. Meyer Seminar Photos, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 57)
  - McGovern Seminar Photos, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 58)
  - St. Lukes Photos, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 59)
  - Scrapbook - Women's Fund - "Through the Years, Pictures, and Memories!", undated (Box 34, Item 1)
- Guest Books, 1981-1997
  Two guest books accompanied the collection of materials donated to the UH Archives. Neither is identified and only one has entries.
  - Guest Book, 1981-1987 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Guest Book, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Austin Office, 1987-1991
  In 1987 several directors of the Women's Fund transferred to Austin and decided to expand the services of the Women's Fund to the Austin community. Membership in the Austin branch was more diverse and included many career women. By 1991 it was clear that the Austin office could not sustain itself and the branch was closed. Records follow original order closely but were regrouped slightly to reflect the organizational pattern of the Houston office records.
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Executive Committee, 1987-1990 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Executive Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Financial Records, 1986-1991 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Programs, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Publicity, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Sales Tax Exemption, 1984-1990 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- VHS Programs Library, 1991-1999
  A total of 44 VHS video tapes are listed in chronological order from 1991-1999. The tapes feature guest speakers at various John P. McGovern seminars, lectures, Membership Coffees, and Outreach Events. They are arranged in the box from bottom to top, in chronological order, with the most recent events on top.
  - Tis' the Season to be Jolly: Managing Holiday Stress - Travis Peterson, MSW, Four Season Hotel, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Preparing for Unexpected Financial & Emotional Loss - R. H. Stevens, Jr., CPA, The Forum, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Addiction: Feeding a Hungry Heart - Carl M. Anderson, PhD., INNOVA, 20 Greenway Plaza, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Beauty and the Beast, Battle Against Breast Cancer - Dixie Melillo, MD, HL&P Energy Info. Center Auditorium, 1992 (Box 14)
  - The Challenge of Inner Space, Mental Illness - Stuart C. Yudofsky, MD, St. John the Divine Episcopal Church, 1992 (Box 14)
  - A Celebration of Hope in the Season of "Bright Sadness" - The Rev. Chris C. Steel, 1992 (Box 14)
    Host: Mrs. Jane Cizik
  - Prime Time Women - B. J. Frye, E. Rosborough, E. Tinsley, Junior League of Houston, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Heart to Heart Seminar - Karen Rose, K. Kerfoot, PhD., G. Binder, MD, S. Wilansky, MD, St. Luke's Medical Tower, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Towering Panic - Jaimie Cochran, MD, 1993 (Box 14)
    Host: Mrs. Linda Gillman
  - The Latest & Greatest in New Technology - L. Watts, PhD., S. Pinero, MD, J. W. Walsh, MD, C. Fife, MD, R. Ruiz, MD, Hermann Hospital, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Interaction & Overmedication of Prescription & Over-the-Counter Drugs - Frank E. Smith, MD, 1993 (Box 14)
    Host: Mrs. Joyce Goodman
  - Breaking the Silence - Judith McFarlane, RN, Carol Gee, B.A., Jeffry A. Basen-Enquist, M.A., Houston Area Women Center, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Adv. Genetic Technologies to Diseases of Women - Joe Leigh Simpson, MD, Houston Marriott Medical Center, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Oh, My Aching Feet - John O. Bishop, MD, Houston Civic Garden Center, 1994 (Box 14)
  - My Life, My Body - Dr. Karlene M. Kerfoot, Dr. Esta Kronberg, Jewish Community Center Auditorium, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Alternative Health Care - K. Rogers L.Ac., J. Martine D.C., G. Manso, MD, Omni Houston Hotel, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Life Changes; The Changing Decades: Women's Health Issues - R. Fish, MD, Fae Garden, MD, J. Buster, MD, B. Barrett, MD, The Wyndham Warwick, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Allergies: The Immune System Overreaction - William T. Shearer, MD, PhD., The Forum, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Caring: The Knot at the End of the Rope - Sue Baier, Author of the book: "Bad Number Ten," The Forum, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Third Annual Women's & Girl's Good Health Day, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Hot Zones in Infectious Diseases Today - Irene Fuentez, MD, Herber Dupont, MD, Marcia Kielhofner, MD, St. Luke's Episcopal Hospital, 1995 (Box 14)
  - The Mind is at the Heart of the Body - Alice Domar, PhD., Memorial Health System, 1995 (Box 14)
  - The Women's Fund 13th Annual Benefit Luncheon - Janice Woods Windle, Author of "True Women," Westin Galleria Hotel, 1995 (Box 14)
  - Reversing Heart Disease: Is it Possible? - Antonio Grotto, Jr. MD, 1995 (Box 14)
    Host: Mrs. Odessa Wexler
  - Those Marvelous and Maddening Hormones - Elizabeth Lee Vliet, MD, Junior League of Houston, 1995 (Box 14)
  - Self-Defense for Women - Holly and Kevin Bozant, The Forum, 1995 (Box 14)
  - The New Renovated Clinical Nursing Skill Lab - Kathryn Stream, Ph.D, Assistant Vice President of TWA, 1995 (Box 14)
    Tour Guide: Joan Devilbiss, Texas Women University
  - Ovarian Cancer Screening: What You Need to Know - Joseph A. Lucci III, MD, St. Joseph Hospital, 1996 (Box 14)
  - Embracing Change: You Only Have 'One Life to Live' - Elizabeth Gregory, Ph.D, Cynthia Freeland, Ph.D, Junior League of Houston, 1996 (Box 14)
  - Good Grief, Charlie Brown - Karen Pennebaker, St. John the Divine Episcopal Church, 1996 (Box 14)
  - Biochemistry of the Aging Process - James R. Gullett, MD, Sports Fitness Center Auditorium, One Fannin Building, 1996 (Box 14)
  - Women's Health - Past, Present, and Future - Kathryn Peek, Ph.D, The University Club, 1996 (Box 14)
  - Too Much of a Good Thing? - Eileen Starbranch, MD and Hope Nordmeyer, LMSW-ASCP, Houston Country Club, 1996 (Box 14)
  - The Heart of the Matter - Philip Bentliff, MD, Patrick Hogan, MD, Stephanie Gross, MD, Ricer Oaks Country Club, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Everyday Aches and Pain - Heidi Seifert Collins, MD, and Bill Case PT, SCS, The Briar Club, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Entering and Leaving the Sandwich Generation - Anita Woods, Ph.D, Sharon K. Oswald, Ph.D, Nancy L. Wilson, M.A., Junior League of Houston, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Learning From Your Body Teacher - Rita Justice, Ph.D, 1998 (Box 14)
    Host: Joyce Goodman
  - The Biology of Attachment - Patricia Love, Ed.D, Omni Houston Hotel, 1998 (Box 14)
  - What's Up Doc? - Cheryl Alston, MD, The Forum, 1998 (Box 14)
  - Everyday Depression - William H. Boytston, MD and Alice M. Gates, Ed.D, Junior League of Houston, 1998 (Box 14)
  - Looking Backward and Looking Ahead - Raymond H. Kaufman, MD, The Forum, 1999 (Box 14)
  - 20th Anniversary Luncheon - Celebration of Leadership - Doris Kearns Goodwin, Westin Galleria Hotel, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Primer on Women's Health - Christi Myer's 5 p.m. Newcast (Box 14)
  - Alternatives to Hysterectomy, KHOU - TV, Houston, Dr. Joseph Feste (Box 14)